cornell.edu 2018-12-26

# Privacy Notice | Cornell University

The following privacy notice describes what information we collect from you when you visit [www.cornell.edu](http://www.cornell.edu/) and how we use this information. Please read this privacy notice carefully so that you understand our privacy practices. 

##  Effective Date of Privacy Notice 

The privacy notice was last revised on June 13, 2018. 

##  What information we gather during your visit 

_Information we gather:_

We automatically collect certain information from you when you visit [www.cornell.edu](http://www.cornell.edu/). This data is used in conjunction with Google Analytics to gather metrics on site usage including geographic location of visitors, pathways navigated through the website, and which portion of our audience is internal to the Cornell network. The information we collect is not linked to anything that identifies you as an individual. Your session will be tracked but you will remain anonymous as a user. As part of Google Analytics, we also gather device and browser-related information. 

_Information you may provide:_

We may also collect other information as described in this notice or other specific university privacy notices. In order to take full advantage of some of our services, certain tools, such as the [plan your visit tool](http://www.cornell.edu/visit/), the [university events calendar](http://events.cornell.edu/) and [events emailer](https://www.cornell.edu/events-emailer/), and the [CornellCast video library](http://www.cornell.edu/video/) may request additional contact information and/or online identifiers (ex. supplied username or NetID). 

## How we use your information

We use gathered information to track user trends and site usage with the goal of improving our visitors’ experience and optimizing our websites. We also use the information to administer this website and prevent abuse. 

_Special cases:_

If you use the [plan your visit](http://www.cornell.edu/visit/), service the information that is gathered may be used to send you postal mail or email, or in some cases, it may be used to contact you via phone pertaining to your visit to the university. Additionally, the information gathered may be used for admissions-related purposes such as sending you information about enrollment to the university if you self-identify as a prospective undergraduate or graduate student. 

The [events emailer](https://www.cornell.edu/events-emailer/) service associates your email address with preferences you provide for receiving email notifications based on various user-selected criteria pertaining to emailing you about upcoming events. We aggregate reports about preferences but do not correlate them with the email addresses. 

The [CornellCast video library](http://www.cornell.edu/video/) has an optional feature that allows you to sign up for email reminders before a live broadcast of your choice begins. Your email address will only be used for communicating with you about the live broadcast. Additionally, you may provide your email address during a live broadcast to ask or receive follow up to questions that were not addressed during the broadcast. 

## With whom we share your information

Information we gather may also be shared with campus constituents to improve programs, outreach, and other campus initiatives. Additionally, metrics may be shared with vendors to improve communications related to these activities. However, we will not sell this data to third-parties for their use in direct marketing, advertising, or for the promotion of their products and services. 

_Special cases:_

The [university events calendar](http://events.cornell.edu/) is powered by a third-party vendor, [Localist](https://www.localist.com/), and its usage is subject to its [terms of service](https://www.localist.com/legal/terms/) and [privacy policy](https://www.localist.com/legal/privacy-policy/). 

## Cookies and other collection technologies

_Cookies_

Cookies are text files stored on your computer and accessible only to the websites which create them. 

Our websites may use cookies to keep you logged into secure areas of the website and/or to keep track of your preferences as you interact with certain services. You may disable cookies in your browser, however, our websites may not work properly if you do so. 

_Log Files_

Our websites automatically gather anonymous information about our visitors including IP addresses, browser types, and the times and dates of webpage visits. The information collected does not include any personally identifiable details and is used to improve our services and administer our websites. 

## Protecting your information

No method of transmitting over the internet or storing electronic data is 100% secure, but this site has measures in place to help protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of the information that is under our control. 

## Email Marketing

Marketing emails you may receive from the university contain options to unsubscribe. However, there are certain internal or safety-related email messages that are delivered to all Cornell University community members that will not contain an opt-out option as these are considered critical internal communications. 

## Social Media Presence

If you share our content through social media, such as liking us on Facebook or tweeting about us on Twitter, those social networks will record that you have done so and may set a cookie for this purpose. 

If you wish to opt-out of any of these social interactions please refer to the specific social media platform for instructions on how to do so. 

## External Website Links

From time-to-time, we will link to external websites that we neither own nor control. Cornell University is not responsible for the content, privacy practices, or web accessibility needs on these websites. 

## Special Notice for EU Residents

If you are located within the European Economic Area (European Union, Norway, Liechtenstein, and Iceland), we acknowledge the rights granted to you under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). 

These rights may include:  

  1. Right to access your information held by us
  2. Right to correct inaccurate or incorrect information about you
  3. Right to the erasure of your information when it is no longer necessary for us to retain it
  4. Right to restrict processing of your personal information in specific situations
  5. Right to object to processing your information, including sending you communications that may be considered direct-marketing materials
  6. Right to object to automated decision-making and profiling, where applicable
  7. Right to complain to a supervisory authority in your jurisdiction within the EU

Please contact us with any questions, concerns, or if you wish to exercise any of these rights: [gdpr@cornell.edu](mailto:gdpr@cornell.edu)

## Contact Information

If you have questions about our privacy notice or the privacy practices it describes, please contact: [privacy@cornell.edu](mailto:privacy@cornell.edu).
